A Finding Aid to the Jan Butterfield Papers, 1950-1997, in the Archives of American Art AAA.buttjan
Archives of American Art
- Project Files, circa 1950-1990; Series 3; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 8-10, 16
  - The Art Collection of Pacific Enterprises Artist Files and Interviews, circa 1990; 3.1; 1 Linear feet (Box 8)
    Records related to a published catalog of the corporate art collection of Pacific Enterprises include galleys of artist biographies as they appeared in the book, a typescript glossary of terms related to artworks in the collection, and nine sound cassettes (microcassettes) containing artist interviews conducted by Michael Karp. Microcassettes have poor sound quality, and the artists being interviewed are not named or consistently identified in cassette labels. Those who have been identified are listed in the folder listing, below, in the order in which their interviews occur on the cassette. Interviews tend to be around 20 minutes in duration.
    Artist files generally contain typescript artist biographies, resumes obtained from galleries or from the artist, photocopies of clippings and articles related to the artist, and sometimes contain exhibition printed material and photographs of artwork. Most of the biographies were written by Micahel Karp, but a few were written by Butterfield, including biographies for Arleo, Breschi, Ruth Duckworth, Kenneth Ferguson, David Gilhooly, Tom Marioni, Richard Shaw, Inez Storer, and Peter Voulkos. Note that files do not exist for every artist that was included in the Pacific Enterprises Catalog.
    Additional artist files maintained by Jan Butterfield can be found in the writings series under Publicity Writings when they contain writings produced by Butterfield for the artist, in the Personal Business Records series under Correspondence when they contain correspondence between Butterfield and the artist. Additional artist files containing only reproductions of artwork are found in the Photographs series.
    - Artist Biogrpahies, Galley Proof, circa 1991 (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
    - Glossary, Typescript, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Interviews, circa 1990; 9 Sound cassettes (microcassette) (Box 8, Folder 24-26)
      Microcassette 1 of 9
      John Millei
      Sam Maloof
      David Ireland
      Ron Cooper
      Microcassette 2 of 9
      Ron Cooper (continued)
      Lita Albuquerque
      Gus Foster
      David Kimball Anderson
      Robert Arneson
      Unidentified sculptor
      David Pearson
      Louis Pearson
      Microcassette 3 of 9
      Louis Pearson (continued)
      Guy Dill
      Laddie Dill
      Microcassette 4 of 9
      James Morris
      Howard Buchwald
      Dean Johnson
      Ann Adair
      Microcassette 5 of 9
      Add Adair (continued)
      Tom Marioni
      James Linnehan
      Annette McCormick
      Tim Mather
      Microcassette 6 of 9
      Gillian Theobald (Note with Theobald's name indicates this may be part 2 of this interview, but no part 1 is extant.)
      Keith Milow
      Norma Pechansky Glasser
      Zizi Raymond
      Rosaline Delisle
      Marilyn Levine
      Nelson Valentine
      Frank Romero
      Peter Alexander
      Yoshio Taylor
      Microcassette 7 of 9
      Gretchen Ewart (Note by Ewart's name indicates this is part 2 of the interview, but no part 1 is extant.)
      Skip Miller
      Buelbo (?)
      Richard Deutsch
      Tom Ashcraft
      Microcassette 8 of 9
      Inez Storer
      Jean Lowe
      Eleane Grove
      Andrew Ginzel
      Kristen Jones
      Charles Arnoldi
      Microcassette 9 of 9
      Charles Arnoldi (continued)
      Fran Martin
      Paul Sarkisian
      Carol Sarkisian
      Steven Beye
    - Artist Files (Box 8)
      - Mark Abildgaard, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Ann Adair, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Edward Allington, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - David Anderson, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Adrian Arleo, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - Richard Artschwager, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Bill Barrell, 1982-1985 (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - Joel Bass, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - Bennett Bean, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 35)
      - Howard Ben Tre, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - Roger Berry, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - Derek Boshier, 1988-1990 (Box 8, Folder 38)
      - Nick Boskovich, 1985-1990 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Robert Brady, 1976-1989 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Karen Breschi, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Howard Buchwald, 1975-1989 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - John Buck, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Peter Campus, 1981-1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Dale Chihuly, 1981-1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Annette Corcoran, 1984-1989 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Philip Cornelius, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Ron Davis, 1976-1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Constance De Jong, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Tony DeLap, 1963-1986 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Rosaline Delisle, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Richard Deutsch, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Joseph DiGiorgio, circa 1990 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Guy Dill, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Ruth Duckworth, 1982-1989 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Ibsen Espada, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Ned Evans, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Gretschen Ewart, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Kenneth Ferguson, 1979-1988 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Gus Foster, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Connie Fox, 1986-1990 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - Hermine Freed, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - David Gilhooly, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Norma Glasser, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - Larry Gray, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Red Grooms, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - Eaine Grove, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Al Held, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - Tom Holland, 1974-1988 (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - John Hull, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Jim Huntington, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Phillis Ideal, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Dean Johnson, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Kristin Jones, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - William King, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - Jeff Koons, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 38)
      - Arva Leodas, 1985-1989 (Box 9, Folder 39)
      - Dennis Leon, 1977-1990 (Box 9, Folder 40)
      - Marilyn Levine, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 41)
      - Sol LeWitt, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 42)
      - James Linnehan, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 43)
      - Jean Lowe, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 44)
      - Gregory Mahoney, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 45)
      - Sam Maloof, circa 1990 (Box 9, Folder 46)
      - Tom Marioni, 1974-1990 (Box 9, Folder 47)
      - Fran Martin, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 48)
      - Tim Mather, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 49)
      - David McClear, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 50)
      - Annette McCormick, 1986-1990 (Box 9, Folder 51)
      - John Millei, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 52)
      - Skip Miller, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 53)
      - Keith Milow, 1982-1990 (Box 9, Folder 54)
      - Mike Moran, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 55)
      - Jesús Bautista Moroles, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 56)
      - James Morris, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 57)
      - Jay Musler, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 58)
      - Ronna Neuenschwander, 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 59)
      - John Nygren, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 60)
      - Eric Orr, 1980-1989 (Box 9, Folder 61)
      - Shauna Peck, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 62)
      - Jeff Perone, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 63)
      - Judy Pfaff, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 64)
      - Zizi Raymond, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 65)
      - John Register, circa 1989 (Box 9, Folder 66)
      - Frank Romero, 1984-1989 (Box 9, Folder 67)
      - James Rosenquist, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 68)
      - Carol Sarkisian, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 69)
      - Paul Sarkisian, 1982-1987 (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - Adrian Saxe, 1985-1990 (Box 9, Folder 71)
      - Italo Scanga, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Sean Scully, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 73)
      - Richard Shaw, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 74)
      - Peter Shire, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Marion Stiebel, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Sandy Skogland, 1981-1989 (Box 9, Folder 77)
      - David Smith, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 78)
      - Pat Steir, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 79)
      - Inez Storer, 1987-1990 (Box 9, Folder 80)
      - Roger Sweet, circa 1990 (Box 9, Folder 81)
      - Yoshio Taylor, 1982-1990 (Box 9, Folder 82)
      - Gillian Theobald, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 83)
      - Gwen Thomas, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 84)
      - John Torreano, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 85)
      - Leo Valledor, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 86)
      - Peter Voulkos, 1975-1990 (Box 9, Folder 87)
        Oversized material moved to box 16, folder 2.
      - Peter Waite, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 88)
      - Roscoe West, 1976-1989 (Box 9, Folder 89)
      - Margaret Wharton, 1981-1987 (Box 9, Folder 90)
      - Sheila Wolk, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 91)
      - Elizabeth Woodman, 1978-1988 (Box 9, Folder 92)
    - Oversized material from The Art Collection of Pacific Enterprises, Artist Files, Peter Voulkos (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 9, folder 87.
  - Waterfront Project Photographs and Sound Recordings, 1976-1978; 3.2; 0.4 Linear feet (Box 10)
    Jan Butterfield coordinated the waterfront project while on the faculty of the San Francisco Art Institute. The project began in 1976 was modeled on the La Defense project in Paris, which involved local artists in urban planning of a blighted area. Participants in the project included Butterfield, Larry Bell, Robert Irwin, Melinda Wortz, Eric Orr, Dr. E. Wortz, Frank Gehry, Newton and Helen Harrison, and Josh Young, as well as students at the Art Institute. The project and was designed to take a cross-disciplinary approach to urban planning and development for the waterfront district of San Francisco, and to involve artists and local residents in decision-making. Records relating to the project found in this series include photographs of meetings and waterfront scenes, most of which are credited to Jan Butterfield, and sound recordings of meetings, lectures, and literary readings. The lecture by Jan Butterfield contains detailed information about the project as a whole. Sound recordings are on five sound tape reels and 1 sound cassette.
    Fragments of additional taped meetings are found on reels that were recycled for Butterfield's interviews. See series 1, interviews and lectures, David Hockney interview and John Cage performance and lecture.
    - Photographs, circa 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Sound Recordings (Box 10)
      - Waterfront Meeting, Frank Gehry's, 1977 July 6; 1 sound tape reels (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Waterfront Lecture, Melinda Wortz, 1977 September; 1 sound tape reels (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Waterfront Class with Josh Young, 1977 September 16; 1 sound tape reels (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Waterfront Class with Toby Rosenblatt, Audrey Owen, Bob Moyer, 1977 October 21; 1 sound tape reels (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Lecture by Butterfield at San Francisco Art Institute, 1978 February 6; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Literary Reading by Waterfront Writers, 1978 May; 1 sound tape reels (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Sound Tape Reel Box, Empty, Labeled Waterfront Meeting, Los Angeles, 1977 August 31 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Lapis Press Records, bulk 1984-1988; circa 1950s-1988; 3.3; 0.3 Linear feet (Box 10)
    Lapis Press was a publishing firm Butterfield was involved in. A few scattered records exist in this collection relating to Lapis publications, including a catalog, clippings with cartoons files as "Lapis Jokes," newspaper clippings relating the activities of the press, and two interviews on two sound cassettes with unidentified scholars of Carl Jung, possibly including one with C.A. Meyer, the author of Lapis publication Soul and Body. One of the interviews is falsely labeled Jean Star Untermeyer, but could not have been her as it post-dates her death. Also found are a number of photographs that were collected for Lapis publications, including copy negatives for Dorothea Tanning's Birthday, photographs of San Francisco beat-era writers from various sources for the book Whitman's Wild Children, and photographs of an unidentified publishing event.
    - Catalog, circa 1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Lapis Jokes, circa 1984-1988 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Interviews Related to Soul and Body by C.A. Meier, circa 1986; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Photographs (Box 10)
      - Birthday by Dorothea Tanning, circa 1986; Copy negatives (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Whitman's Wild Children by Neeli Cherkovski, circa 1950-1986 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
        Oversized material moved to Box 16, folder 2.
      - Unidentified Event, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Publicity, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Oversized Materials from Lapis Press Records, Photographs, Whitman's Wild Children (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 10, folder 10.
- Personal Business Records, 1967-1996; Series 4; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 10-11, OV 17-19 (Box 10)
  A copy of the periodical The Journal of Art, which has records in this series, is found in series 5, Printed Materials. Additional press releases are also foundin seris 5, Printed Materials.
  This series contains records relating to Butterfield's sale and appraisal of artworks, correspondence relating to her writing and publicity work for artists, other records relating to her career including detailed resumes, and a few personal records relating to her family, friends, finances and health. Also found is 1 sound cassette from Butterfield's answering machine containing incoming messages and some phone conversations from the early 1980s.
  Correspondence files also contain many enclosures, including contracts, postcards, photographs of works of art, and printed materials. The file on the Los Angeles Cultural Affairs Commission contains extensive writings and other documentation relating to the sculptor George Herms, the subject of an exhibition at the municipal art gallery, Barnsdall Park.
  - Art Sales and Loans (Box 10)
    - Price Lists, 1990-1999 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - John Natsoulas Gallery, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Sam Francis, 1984-1994 (Box 10, Folder 16-18)
    - Santa Monica Auctions, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Authentication of Gauguin's Vue du Port du Martinique, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Business License, The Journal of Art, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence (Box 10)
    - Outgoing, 1988-1995 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Personal, circa 1970, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Business, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Archives of American Art, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - AICA (Association Internationale des Critiques d'Art), 1991 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Christina Chalmers, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Janet Disraeli, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Tom Eatherton, 1967-1981 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Venessa Falgoust, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Walter Hopps and Elizabeth Shepherd, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Eric Johnson, circa 1994-1996; Includes 2 videocassettes (VHS) contianing studio footage. (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - David Jones, 1987-1993 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Los Angeles Cultural Commission regarding George Herms Exhibition, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Eric Orr, 1983-1991 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Stuart Collection, University of California San Diego, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Calvin Tomkins, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Bill Witherspoon, 1990-1992 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Financial Records (Box 11)
    - Personal, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Professional, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Job Search, 1990-1994 (Box 11, Folder 3-7)
  - Notes, circa 1983-1994 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    Oversized material moved to Box 18.
  - Press Releases (Box 11)
    - Death of Richard Brown, Kimball Art Museum, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Henry Hopkins, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Résumés and CVs (Box 11)
    - Jan Butterfield, 1980-1994 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Henry Hopkins, circa 1974 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Telephone Messages, circa 1981; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified Technical Drawing, circa 1970-1990 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Oversized material moved to Box 19.
  - Oversized Personal Business Records, Press Releases, Death of Richard Brown (Box 17)
    Oversized material from Box 11, folder 9.
  - Oversized Personal Business Records, Notes (Box 18)
  - Oversized Personal Business Records, Unidentified Technical Drawing (Box 19)
    Oversized material from Box 11, folder 14.
- Printed Materials, 1961-1997; Series 5; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 11-12, 16, OV 17-19
  This series contains articles published in magazines, newspapers, journals, and other art-related publications, as well as exhibition catalogs, posters, plans for installations and exhibition spaces, a disassembled scrapbook, and special print publications. Many of the articles and clippings exist in photocopy only.
  Any printed material containing writings by Butterfield is filed at the beginning of the series under "Articles by Butterfield." A bound collection of article photocopies is found at the beginning of the series, followed by early articles Butterfield wrote for Texas papers between 1970-1972. Individual articles by Butterfield are then filed by artist's name, or by the title of the article if the subject was not a single artist. Clippings have a few files arranged by subject, but most clippings are filed chronologically. A few clippings files also contain press releases. Most of the articles are about specific artists, galleries, museums, and other art world stories. Exhibition catalogs are arranged alphabetically by artist or by exhibition title for group shows. Additional exhibition catalogs are found in the Writings series, among Butterfield's drafts of catalog essays and publicity writings. An exhibition program for Tony Labat is filed under "Articles by Butterfield."
  Exhibition posters are for Ferus Gallery from 1963 and Robert Hudson at Moore College in 1978. Plans include two floor plans of installations by James Turrell, one axonometric view of an unidentified installation, and two elevation drawings of P.S.1 in Queens, New York. Publicity files are arranged by subject and contain multiple types of printed material such as press releases, clippings, exhibition catalogs, and announcements. Readings for "Issues in Contemporary Art" contains photocopied articles used by Butterfield to teach a college course of that name.
  Special publications include magazines and other printed matter which Butterfield collected or contributed to, including two issues of the program for the Artists' Soapbox Derby at the San Francisco Museum of Art and a 1978 guide to art spaces published by the Los Angeles Institute of Contemporary Art.
  Additional printed materials are found in series 2, Writings, series 3, Project files, and series 4, Personal Business Records.
  - Articles by Butterfield (Box 11)
    - Bound Portfolio, circa 1985 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Fort Worth Star-Telegram, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Texas Observer, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - "Context: Light and Space as Art", 1982 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "The Russians Are Coming", 1980 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Lita Albuquerque, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Larry Bell, 1978, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Fletcher Benton, 1980, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Joan Brown, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Chris Burden, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Judy Chicago, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Christo, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Richard Diebenkorn, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Sam Francis, 1979-1983 (Box 11, Folder 28-29)
    - Joe Goode, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Philip Guston, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - George Herms, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Robert Hudson, 1976, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Robert Irwin, 1972-1981 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Oliver Jackson, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Craig Kaufman, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 36)
      Oversized materials moved to Box 16, folder 3.
    - Tony Labat, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 37)
      Oversized material moved to Box 16, folder 3.
    - Modesto Lanzone, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Helen Lundberg, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Bruce Nauman, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Manuel Neri, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Maria Nordman, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Joseph Raffael, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - George Segal, circa 1984 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Wayne Thiebaud, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - James Turrell, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - "Those Were the Days: L.A. in the 60s", 1981 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Article by Henry Hopkins, "West Coast Style", 1966 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Articles about Butterfield (Box 11)
    - Art of Light and Space Review, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Lapis Press, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Art Over the Sofa Exhibition, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Clippings (Box 11)
    - Family, 1961-1971 (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Sam Francis, 1979-1994 (Box 11, Folder 53)
      Also contains funeral mass program.
      Oversized materials moved to Box 16, folder 4.
    - Henry Hopkins, 1968-1991 (Box 11, Folder 54-55)
    - Peter Erskine, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - General Clippings, 1968-1975 (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - General Clippings, 1979-1989 (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - General Clippings, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - General Clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - General Clippings, 1994-1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Exhibition Catalogs (Box 11)
    - 24 Young Los Angeles Artists (1971), Los Angeles County Museum of Art (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - Albright Knox Gallery Acquisitions (1961) (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - The Human Condition (1984), San Francisco Museum of Modern Art Biennial (Box 11, Folder 64)
      Oversized material moved to box 16, folder 5.
    - Jack Brogan: Projects (1980), Baxter Art Gallery (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Fluid Bodies (1996), Gallery 825 (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Sam Francis, 1961, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Sam Francis, 1972-1978 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Sam Francis, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Oversized material moved to Box 16, folder 5.
    - Sam Francis, 1981-1986 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Sam Francis, 1986-1992, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Frimkess (1992), R. Mutt 1917 Gallery (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Impressionist and Post-Impressionist Paintings from the USSR (1973) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - The Paintings of James Kelly, 1952-1990, The Wiegand Gallery (1990) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Ed Kienholz, Los Angeles County Museum of Art (1966) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Light/Motion/Space, Milwaukee Art Center (1967) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - MA: Space-Time in Japan, The Cooper-Hewitt Museum, circa 1979 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - David Maxim: Painted Philosophy (1994), University of California at Berkeley Museums at Blackhawk (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - New Structuralists (1994), Boritzer/Gray/Hamano (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Beverly Pepper: Small-Scale Sculpture and Drawings, Gerald Peters Gallery (1989) (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Ken Price: Figurine Cups, Gemini G.E.L., circa 1970 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Clyfford Still (1976), San Francisco Museum of Modern Art (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Posters (Box 12)
    - Ferus Gallery, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Robert Hudson, Moore College, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Plans, 1976, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Publicity (Box 12)
    - Lee Roy Champagne, circa 1994 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Christo, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Richard Diebenkorn, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Edward Dugmore, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Frederick Eversley, 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Sam Francis, 1980-1985 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Joe Goode, 1988-1992 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Robert Graham, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 27)